# **ANTHONY ETIM**

Address: Yale University, 10 Hillhouse Avenue, New Haven, CT, 06511

Email: anthony.etim@yale.edu Webpage: <a href="https://anthonyedemetim.com/">https://anthonyedemetim.com/</a> Phone Number: +1 (215) 485-8250

https://www.linkedin.com/in/anthony-etim/

#### **RESEARCH INTERESTS**

My research interests lie in computer architecture and security, especially focusing on cloud infrastructures and the security of FPGA-accelerated cloud environments by evaluating and defending various types of side channels and covert channels, as well as how to enable secure multi-tenant Cloud FPGAs.

# **EDUCATION**

Yale University, New Haven, CT

August 2021 – Present

Ph.D. in Electrical Engineering

Research Assistant, Computer Architecture and Security (CAS) Lab.

Advisor: Prof. Jakub Szefer

Villanova University, Villanova, PA B.S. in Electrical Engineering

August 2017 – May 2021

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

**Programming:** C++, C, JavaScript, MATLAB, HTML, CSS, Java, Python, SQL, VHDL, Verilog/ System Verilog, Haskell

Tools: AWS tools, Docker, Xilinx Vivado/ISE, Quartus, Jupyter Notebook

Technological Devices: Raspberry Pi, Arduino

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

- Anthony Etim, Shanquan Tian, and Jakub Szefer. "Extending FPGA Information Leaks with Trojan Phantom Circuits". In Review by the IEEE International Symposium on Secure and Private Execution Environment Design (SEED), 2024.
- Theodoros Trochatos, Anthony Etim, and Jakub Szefer. "Covert-channels in FPGA-enabled SmartSSDs". Accepted by the 22nd International Conference on Field-Programmable Technology (FPT), 2023 Journal Track at ACM Transactions on Reconfigurable Technology and System (TRETS).

### RESEARCH EXPRIENCE

Yale University, Graduate Researcher, New Haven, CT

August 2021 – Present

Exploring information leaks and using Ring Oscillators (ROs) to sense voltage and thermal changes in FPGA-accelerated cloud environments.

Villanova University, Undergraduate Researcher, Villanova, PA

Fall 2020 – Spring 2021

• Developed a deep neural network to achieve a secrecy capacity for efficient, reliable and secure transmission of information.

Villanova University, Undergraduate Researcher, Villanova, PA

Fall 2020

• Used Matrix Singular Value Decomposition (SVD) technique to optimize the deep neural network (DNN) on the AVNET Ultra96-V2 FPGA development board.

• Evaluated the performance, accuracy, and energy consumption of the optimized system.

# Villanova University, Undergraduate Researcher, Villanova, PA

Spring 2020

- Estimated the added value and future costs of coordinated economics dispatch in Central America through the electrical system load.
- Trained the neural network to forecast the electrical system load.

### Villanova University, Undergraduate Researcher, Villanova, PA

Summer 2019

- Collaborated with a team of 3 in conjunction with L3 Harris in the creation of an efficient food purchasing and tracking system for dining services to reduce food waste.
- Developed software system that is simple to populate and used to track purchased quantities and consumption to reduce waste significantly.
- Filed a provisional patent for the software system.

# Villanova University, Undergraduate Researcher, Villanova, PA

March 2018 – May 2019

- Conducted research on the development of the flow network modeling tool Villanova Thermodynamic Analysis of Systems (VTAS), which models the energy flows throughout a data center.
- Upgraded the Graphical User Interface (GUI) for the Villanova Thermodynamic Analysis of Systems (VTAS) data center flow network modeling tool.
- Developed the GUI Interface for the VTAS electrical system layout.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Electrical Engineering Intern, National Grid, Albany, NY, Remote

Summer 2020

- Collaborated with a team of 4 engineers to help reorganize and plan the grid network using various tools.
- Modelled data to fit various design requirements and constraints of the power system.
- Assisted in the management and creation of a SharePoint Setting Repository for the handoff of smart control settings to the field device engineers.
- Collaborated with other engineers to build a database of DMX and control house plans for the grid network.

### Web Developer Intern, Kumba Africa, Philadelphia, PA

Summer 2018

- Built reusable code to be utilized in other projects, effectively streamlining spending.
- Contributed back-end experience and collaborated on APIs.
- Collaborated on the design and development on a team of 4 of client and server database applications.
- Analyzed project requirements to find bugs and eliminate issues within a timely manner.

## TEACHING EXPERIENCE

• **Teaching Fellow,** Yale University, New Haven, CT Introduction to Computer Engineering (EENG 201)

Spring 2023

• **Teaching Fellow,** Yale University, New Haven, CT Introduction to Electronics (EENG 200)

Fall 2022

#### **POSTERS**

- Oct. 2019. Feastimate. Future of Packaging Consortium, Villanova University, PA
- April 2019. Improving the user interface of Data center modeling Software. (Project #1)
   Center for Energy-Smart Electronic Systems, Industrial Advisory Board Meeting at Binghamton University, NY.
- Oct. 2018. Improving the user interface of Data center modeling Software. (Project #1) Center for Energy-Smart Electronic Systems, Industrial Advisory Board Meeting at Villanova University, PA.
- Sep. 2018. Improving the user interface of Data center modeling Software. Undergraduate Research Symposium at Villanova University, PA.

### **SERVICE**

Yale Cloud Computing and FPGA Security Symposium (CCFS) 2022, Co-organizer
 November 2022

• Yale Grad Society of Women Engineers, Undergrad Liaison Co-chair Fall 2022 - Present

# **LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE**

**Tau Beta Pi,** National Engineering Honor Society, Villanova Chapter, Vice-President

March 2020-May 2021

- Planned and conducted various professional events for the chapter's members such as the initiation information session for new members.
- Helped in the advancement of the technical and professional education of the active members by connecting them with various alumni.

# Villanova Engineering Student Council, Co-Chair

September 2019- May 2021

• Planned events for the College of Engineering and acted as a bridge between the students and faculty.

# National Society of Black Engineers, Senator

August 2017-September 2018

April 2019

• Represented Villanova chapter at the 2017 Fall Regional Conference in Greensboro, NC.

### **SELECTED HONORS AND AWARDS**

Klingler Unitas Prize,

<ul> <li>Yale New Student Fellowship</li> </ul>	September 2021
<ul> <li>Dean's Award for Academic Excellence</li> </ul>	May 2021
<ul> <li>Dean's Award for Meritorious Service</li> </ul>	May 2021
<ul> <li>Dean's List</li> </ul>	Every Semester
Klingler Unitas Prize,	April 2020
Villanova Student Entrepreneurship Competition	

Page 3 of 4

Villanova Student Entrepreneurship Competition

• Tau Beta Pi, the National Engineering Honor Society,
Selected based on academic ranking 1/8th of the junior class.

Spring 2020